Guide to the Graphics collection, 1740-1995 MS2379
Special Collections Research Center, The George Washington University
- Graphics, 1740-1995; Series 1
  - [Pennsylvania Avenue, Washington, D.C.], Circa [189-?]]; Series 1; 1 photographic print on stereo card: stereograph, black and white; 9 x 18 cm. (Box 54, Folder 21)
    Original catalog no. GRAPHIC 1759
    Cataloging notes: Title obscured.
  - Penn. Ave. and U.S. Capitol from Treasury Department, Circa [189-?]; Series 1; 1 photographic print on stereo card: stereograph, black and white; 9 x 18 cm. (Box 54, Folder 22)
    Original catalog no. GRAPHIC 1760
    Cataloging notes: Pennsylvania Avenue in Washington, D.C.; Treasury Building shown in middle distance; U.S. Capitol in background; trees in foreground.
  - Penna. Avenue from State Dep't, Wash'n, D.C., Circa [189-?]]; Series 1; 1 photographic print on stereo card: stereograph, black and white; 9 x 18 cm. (Box 54, Folder 23)
    Original catalog no. GRAPHIC 1761
    Cataloging notes: Pennsylvania Avenue in Washington, D.C., seen from the State Department; trees in foreground; Treasury Building and U.S. Capitol shown.
  - Penna. Ave. from U.S. Treasury, Washington, D.C., U.S.A. by Underwood and Underwood., Circa [1892]; Series 1; 1 photographic print on stereo card: stereograph, black and white; 9 x 18 cm. (Box 54, Folder 24)
    Original catalog no. GRAPHIC 1762
    Cataloging notes: Pennsylvania Avenue in Washington, D.C.; probably part of of Grand Army of the Republic parade, 1892.
  - Pennsylvania Ave., from Treasury, Washington, D.C.., Circa [ 1900]; Series 1; 1 photographic print on stereo card: stereograph, black and white; 9 x 18 cm. (Box 54, Folder 25)
    Original catalog no. GRAPHIC 1763
    Cataloging notes: Pennsylvania Avenue in Washington, D.C.; streetcar in foreground; several people crossing the street.
  - Pennsylvania Avenue from the Treasury, N.E. to the United States Capitol, Washington, D.C. by Underwood and Underwood., Circa [1903]; Series 1; 1 photographic print on stereo card: stereograph, black and white; 9 x 18 cm. (Box 54, Folder 26)
    Original catalog no. GRAPHIC 1764
    Cataloging notes: Pennsylvania Avenue in Washington, D.C.; five men and women, all wearing hats, in the foreground.
  - Pennsylvania Ave. from Treasury, Washington, D.C.., Circa [ 1900]; Series 1; 1 photographic print on stereo card: stereograph, black and white; 9 x 18 cm. (Box 54, Folder 27)
    Original catalog no. GRAPHIC 1765
    Cataloging notes: Pennsylvania Avenue in Washington, d.C.; streetcar in center; carriages and people in street.
  - Washington, Pennsylvania Ave. from Treasury by William H. Rau, photographer., Circa [ 1900]; Series 1; 1 photographic print on stereo card: stereograph, black and white; 9 x 18 cm. (Box 54, Folder 28)
    Original catalog no. GRAPHIC 1766
    Cataloging notes: "6942."; Pennsylvania Avenue in Washington, D.C.; streetcar and carriages shown.
  - Pennsylvania Avenue, Washington, D.C., U.S.A.., Circa [ 1900]; Series 1; 1 photographic print on stereo card: stereograph, black and white; 9 x 18 cm. (Box 54, Folder 29)
    Original catalog no. GRAPHIC 1767
    Cataloging notes: "440."; Pennsylvania Avenue, Washington, D.C.; several people crossing the street in foreground; streetcar and carriages in background; several flags flying from the tops of buildings.
  - [United States Capitol with Botanic Garden]., Circa 189-?]; Series 1; 1 photographic print on stereo card: stereograph, black and white; 9 x 18 cm. (Box 54, Folder 30)
    Original catalog no. GRAPHIC 1768
    Cataloging notes: Title supplied by cataloger.; United States Capitol in Washington, D.C. with the greenhouse of United States Botanic Garden in foreground.
  - Pennsylvania Avenue and Capitol: views of Washington and vicinity by J.F. Jarvis., Circa [189-?]; Series 1; 1 photographic print on stereo card: stereograph, black and white; 9 x 18 cm. (Box 54, Folder 31)
    Original catalog no. GRAPHIC 1769
    Cataloging notes: Pennsylvania Avenue in Washington, D.C. in background; part of the Treasury Building, shrubs, and a fence in foreground.
  - From Washington Monument (E) over Agricultural grounds to the Capitol by Underwood and Underwood., Circa [191-?]; Series 1; 1 photographic print on stereo card: stereograph, black and white; 9 x 18 cm. (Box 54, Folder 32)
    Original catalog no. GRAPHIC 1770
    Cataloging notes: "5584."; View of the U.S. Capitol in Washington, D.C., from the Washington Monument.
  - From Washington Monument (N.E.) past General Post Office, Washington by Underwood and Underwood., Circa [191-?]; Series 1; 1 photographic print on stereo card: stereograph, black and white; 9 x 18 cm. (Box 54, Folder 33)
    Original catalog no. GRAPHIC 1771
    Cataloging notes: "(6w)-5583."; View of Washington, D.C. from the Washington Monument.
  - From dome of the Capitol W. down Penn. Ave. to P.O., Washington, U.S.A. by Underwood and Underwood., Circa [191-?]; Series 1; 1 photographic print on stereo card: stereograph, black and white; 9 x 18 cm. (Box 54, Folder 34)
    Original catalog no. GRAPHIC 1772
    Cataloging notes: "(17)-5594."; Pennsylvania Avenue in Washington, D.C. from the dome of the U.S. Capitol.
  - Pennsylvania Avenue from the Treasury, S.E. to Capitol by Underwood and Underwood., Circa [192-?]; Series 1; 1 photographic print on stereo card: stereograph, black and white; 9 x 18 cm. (Box 54, Folder 35)
    Original catalog no. GRAPHIC 1773
    Cataloging notes: "5606."; Pennsylvania Avenue in Washington, D.C., from the Treasury Building; five men and women wearing hats in foreground; cars, streetcar, and horse-drawn carts visible on the street.
  - Statuary in U.S. Capitol: [Ethan Allen] by E. Totherick, photograph., Circa [189-?]; Series 1; 1 photographic print on stereo card: stereograph, black and white; 9 x 18 cm. (Box 54, Folder 36)
    Original catalog no. GRAPHIC 1774
    Cataloging notes: Statue of Ethan Allen, by Larkin Mead, in Statuary Hall in the U.S. Capitol, Washington, D.C.
    Allen, Ethan, 1738-1789 Statues Washington (D.C.) Pictorial works.; National Statuary Hall (United States Capitol, Washington, D.C.) Pictorial works.; United States Capitol (Washington, D.C.) Pictorial works.
  - Bird's eye view of Washington from the U.S. Capitol, Circa [189-?]; Series 1; 1 photographic print on stereo card: stereograph, black and white; 9 x 18 cm. (Box 54, Folder 37)
    Original catalog no. GRAPHIC 1775
    Cataloging notes: Washington, D.C. from the U.S. Capitol; shows Long Bridge and Arlington Heights, Virginia in distance.
  - Bird's-eye view of Washington from dome of the Capitol, Circa [189-?]; Series 1; 1 photographic print on stereo card: stereograph, black and white; 9 x 18 cm. (Box 54, Folder 38)
    Original catalog no. GRAPHIC 1776
    Cataloging notes: Washington, D.C. from the U.S. Capitol; Potomac River in distance.
  - [View of National Statuary Hall], Circa [189-?]; Series 1; 1 photographic print on stereo card: stereograph, black and white; 9 x 18 cm. (Box 54, Folder 39)
    Original catalog no. GRAPHIC 1777
    Cataloging notes: Title supplied by cataloger.; National Statuary Hall in the U.S. Capitol, Washington, D.C.
  - Statuary in U.S. Capitol by E. Totherick, photograph., Circa [189-?]; Series 1; 1 photographic print on stereo card: stereograph, black and white; 9 x 18 cm. (Box 54, Folder 40)
    Original catalog no. GRAPHIC 1778
    Cataloging notes: National Statuary Hall in U.S. Capitol; shows six statues.
  - [United States Capitol], Circa [189-?]; Series 1; 1 photographic print on stereo card: stereograph, black and white; 9 x 18 cm. (Box 54, Folder 41)
    Original catalog no. GRAPHIC 1779
    Cataloging notes: Title supplied by cataloger.; United States Capitol in Washington, D.C.; seen from the side.
  - Capitol: American scenery, Washington, D.C., Circa [189-?]; Series 1; 1 photographic print on stereo card: stereograph, black and white; 9 x 18 cm. (Box 54, Folder 42)
    Original catalog no. GRAPHIC 1780
    Cataloging notes: United States Capitol in Washington, D.C.; partially built conservatory of the U.S. Bontanic Garden in foreground.
  - Pennsylvania Avenue, from the dome of the Capitol photographed by Kilburn Brothers., Circa [189-?]; Series 1; 1 photographic print on stereo card: stereograph, black and white; 9 x 18 cm. (Box 54, Folder 43)
    Original catalog no. GRAPHIC 1781
    Cataloging notes: "2266."; Pennsylvania Avenue, in Washington, D.C., as seen from the Capitol.
  - Washington, the Capitol, panorma from the dome by William H. Rau, photographer., Circa [189-?]; Series 1; 1 photographic print on stereo card: stereograph, black and white; 9 x 18 cm. (Box 54, Folder 44)
    Original catalog no. GRAPHIC 1782
    Cataloging notes: "10056."
  - View of Washington City by G.D. Wakely., Circa [1866]; Series 1; 1 photographic print on stereo card: stereograph, black and white; 9 x 17 cm. (Box 54, Folder 45)
    Original catalog no. GRAPHIC 1783
    Cataloging notes: View of Washington, D.C., possibly from the dome of the U.S. Capitol.
  - [United States Capitol with United States Botanic Garden]., Circa [ 1990]; Series 1; 1 photographic print on stereo card: stereograph, black and white; 9 x 18 cm. (Box 55, Folder 1)
    Original catalog no. GRAPHIC 1784
    Cataloging notes: United States Capitol in Washington, D.C. with the United States Botanic Garden in foreground.
  - Penn. Ave. from U.S. Treasury Dep't, Washington., Circa 189-?]; Series 1; 1 photographic print on stereo card: stereograph, black and white; 9 x 18 cm. (Box 55, Folder 2)
    Original catalog no. GRAPHIC 1785
    Cataloging notes: Pennsylvania Avenue in Washington, D.C.; trolley and several horse-drawn carriages in street.
  - [Statue at the United States Capitol]., Circa [ 1900]; Series 1; 1 photographic print on stereo card: stereograph, black and white; 9 x 18 cm. (Box 55, Folder 3)
    Original catalog no. GRAPHIC 1786
    Cataloging notes: United States Capitol; statue The Rescue by Horatio Greenough.
    Greenough, Horatio, 1805-1852. Rescue Pictorial works.; United States Capitol (Washington, D.C.) Pictorial works.
  - Views of Washington and vicinity, Circa [189-?]; Series 1; 1 photographic print on stereo card: stereograph, black and white; 0 x 18 cm. (Box 55, Folder 4)
    Original catalog no. GRAPHIC 1787
    Cataloging notes: Lunette of Columbus arriving in America, in the United States Capitol.
  - Tip-top House: summit of Mt. Washington, 1860: White Mountain scenery photographed by John P. Soule., Circa [1860]; Series 1; 1 photographic print on stereo card: stereograph, black and white; 9 x 17 cm. (Box 55, Folder 5)
    Original catalog no. GRAPHIC 1788
    Cataloging notes: " No. 35."; Group of men and women standing at the top of Mount Washington, New Hampshire.
    Washington, Mount (N.H.) Pictorial works.; New Hampshire Mount Washington. fast http://id.worldcat.org/fast/01333793; Pictorial works. fast http://id.worldcat.org/fast/01423874
  - President's House, Washington, D.C., south front., Circa 189-?]; Series 1; 1 photographic print on stereo card: stereograph, black and white; 9 x 18 cm. (Box 55, Folder 6)
    Original catalog no. GRAPHIC 1789
    Cataloging notes: South face of the White House in Washington, D.C.; fountain in foreground.
  - U.S. Patent Office where fortunes have been secured for inventors, Washington, U.S.A. [picture] by Underwood and Underwood., Circa [1904]; Series 1; 1 photographic print on stereophonic card: stereograph, black and white; 9 x 18 cm. (Box 55, Folder 7)
    Original catalog no. GRAPHIC 1790
    Cataloging notes: "(32w)."; Building constructed starting in 1836 at 8th and F Streets, N.W., Washington, D.C.; formerly U.S. Patent Office, now houses the National Portrait Gallery; horse-drawn carriages shown in street.
  - [Canopy of United States Capitol]: Washington City, and vicinity by T.W. Smillie, photographer., Circa 189-?]; Series 1; 1 photographic print on stereo card: stereograph, black and white; 9 x 18 cm. (Box 55, Folder 8)
    Original catalog no. GRAPHIC 1791
    Cataloging notes: Main title supplied by cataloger.; Allegorical painting by Constantino Brumidi, on canopy of the U.S. Capitol.
    Brumidi, Constantino, 1805-1880. http://id.loc.gov/authorities/names/n81133845; Brumidi, Constantino, 1805-1880. fast http://id.worldcat.org/fast/00082527; United States Capitol (Washington, D.C.) Pictorial works.; United States Capitol (Washington, D.C.) fast http://id.worldcat.org/fast/00631067; Pictorial works. fast http://id.worldcat.org/fast/01423874
  - Gen'l Post Office, Washington., Circa [187-?]; Series 1; 1 photographic print on stereophonic card: stereograph, black and white; 9 x 18 cm (Box 55, Folder 9)
    Original catalog no. GRAPHIC 1792
  - Washington from dome of Capitol, northwest view: American scenery, Washington, D.C., Circa 189-?]; Series 1; 1 photographic print on stereo card: stereograph, black and white; 9 x 18 cm. (Box 55, Folder 10)
    Original catalog no. GRAPHIC 1793
    Cataloging notes: "48."; Washington, D.C. from the dome of the U.S. Capitol.
  - [Washington from dome of the United States Capitol, northwest view]., Circa 189-?]; Series 1; 1 photographic print on stereo card: stereograph, black and white; 9 x 18 cm. (Box 55, Folder 11)
    Original catalog no. GRAPHIC 1794
    Cataloging notes: Title supplied by cataloger.; Washington, D.C., from the dome of the U.S. Capitol, northwest view.
  - Interior U.S. Capitol: Washington, D.C.: old House of Representatives., Circa [ 1900]; Series 1; 1 photographic print on stereo card: stereograph, black and white; 9 x 18 cm. (Box 55, Folder 12)
    Original catalog no. GRAPHIC 1795
    Cataloging notes: Statues in Old House of Representatives, U.S. Capitol; also paintings.
  - Washington City, and vicinity by T.W. Smillie, photographer., Circa 189-?]; Series 1; 1 photographic print on stereo card: stereograph, black and white; 9 x 18 cm. (Box 55, Folder 13)
    Original catalog no. GRAPHIC 1796
    Cataloging notes: View of a building at Soldiers' Home. Established in 1851 as the Military Asylum; name changed in 1859 to Soldiers' Home and in 1972 to the United States Soldiers' and Airmen's Home.
  - [United States Patent Office]: Rice's stereoscopic views, in and around the Capitol., Circa [189-?]; Series 1; 1 photographic print on stereophonic card: stereograph, black and white; 9 x 18 cm. (Box 55, Folder 14)
    Original catalog no. GRAPHIC 1798
    Cataloging notes: Main title constructed by cataloger.; Building constructed starting in 1836 at 8th and F Streets, N.W., Washington, D.C.; formerly U.S. Patent Office, now houses the National Portrait Gallery. Seen from the side.
  - Aqueduct Bridge, Georgetown: Metropolitan and suburban scenery, Washington, D.C.: United States views by W.M. Chase., Circa [189-?]; Series 1; 1 photographic print on stereo card: stereograph, black and white; 9 x 18 cm. (Box 55, Folder 15)
    Original catalog no. GRAPHIC 1799
    Cataloging notes: "1071."; Potomac Aqueduct Bridge, begun 1833, opened 1843, converted to vehicular bridge 1886, dismantled 1934.
    Aqueduct Bridge (Washington, D.C., and Va.) Pictorial works.; United States Aqueduct Bridge. fast http://id.worldcat.org/fast/01334341; Pictorial works. fast http://id.worldcat.org/fast/01423874
  - Washington City, and vicinity by T.W. Smillie, photographer., Circa 189-?]; Series 1; 1 photographic print on stereo card: stereograph, black and white; 9 x 18 cm. (Box 55, Folder 16)
    Original catalog no. GRAPHIC 1800
    Cataloging notes: No Washingtoniana Vertical File number.; Side view of the White House; several people standing in foreground.
    White House (Washington, D.C.) Pictorial works.; White House (Washington, D.C.) fast http://id.worldcat.org/fast/00631324; Photography, Stereoscopic. http://id.loc.gov/authorities/subjects/sh85101299; Photography, Stereoscopic. fast http://id.worldcat.org/fast/01062006; Pictorial works. fast http://id.worldcat.org/fast/01423874
  - View at Washington, numbers 706., Circa [ 1900]; Series 1; 1 photographic print on stereo card: stereograph, black and white; 8 x 17 cm. (Box 55, Folder 17)
    Original catalog no. GRAPHIC 1801
    Cataloging notes: Title from ink inscription on verso.; View of Washington, D.C.; small portion of large building in foreground.
  - [United States Capitol with fence in foreground]., Circa [ 1900]; Series 1; 1 photographic print on stereo card: stereograph, black and white; 8 x 17 cm. (Box 55, Folder 18)
    Original catalog no. GRAPHIC 1802
    Cataloging notes: Title constructed by cataloger.; United States Capitolin Washington, D.C.; trees and fence in foreground.
  - Bird's eye view of Washington from the U.S. Capitol, Circa [ 1900]; Series 1; 1 photographic print on stereo card: stereograph, black and white; 9 x 18 cm. (Box 55, Folder 19)
    Original catalog no. GRAPHIC 1803
    Cataloging notes: View of Washington, D.C. from the dome of the U.S. Capitol building.
  - Land Department numbers 1., Circa [ 1900]; Series 1; 1 photographic print on stereo card: stereograph, black and white; 8 x 17 cm. (Box 55, Folder 20)
    Original catalog no. GRAPHIC 1804
    Cataloging notes: Title from notation on verso.; Columned building, probably in Washington, D.C.
  - [Statue in Washington, D.C.]., Circa [187-?]; Series 1; 1 photographic print on stereo card: stereograph, black and white; 9 x 18 cm. (Box 55, Folder 21)
    Original catalog no. GRAPHIC 1805
    Cataloging notes: Statue of a woman in classical dress, possibly in Washington, D.C.
  - Prince Henry in Washington, arriving at the Capitol to visit the Senate and House of Representatives by H.C. White Company., Circa [1902]; Series 1; 1 photographic print on stereo card: stereograph, black and white; 9 x 18 cm. (Box 55, Folder 22)
    Original catalog no. GRAPHIC 1806
    Cataloging notes: "8173."; Prince Henry (probably Heinrich, Prince of Prussia) in a carriage outside the U.S. Capitol.
    Heinrich, Prince of Prussia, 1862-1929 Portraits.; Heinrich, Prince of Prussia, 1862-1929. fast http://id.worldcat.org/fast/00178511; Portraits. fast http://id.worldcat.org/fast/01423831
  - U.S. Bureau of Engraving and Printing, Dec. 3, 1912 by J. Henry Miller, Incorporated., Circa 1912]; Series 1; 1 photographic print: black and white; 19 x 24 cm. (Box 55, Folder 23)
    Original catalog no. GRAPHIC 1807
    Cataloging notes: U.S. Bureau of Engraving and Printing, in Washington, D.C.; building at 14th and B Streets, SW, occupied 1880-1914.
  - [Pennsylvania Avenue, Washington, D.C.]., Circa [ 1900]; Series 1; 1 photographic print: black and white; 13 x 10 cm. (Box 55, Folder 24)
    Original catalog no. GRAPHIC 1808
    Cataloging notes: Pennsylvania Avenue, Washington, D.C.; Old Post Office building shown; several horse-drawn carriages and people walking in the street.
  - Interior view of St. John's Church, Lafayette Square, Washington, D.C. by Charles Baptie., Circa [ 1970]; Series 1; 1 photomechanical reproduction: color; 9 x 14 cm. (Box 55, Folder 25)
    Original catalog no. GRAPHIC 1809
    Cataloging notes: Post card of interior of St. John's Church, 1525 H Street, Washington, D.C.
  - Grand staircase, Library of Congress, Washington, D.C.., Circa [ 1900]; Series 1; 1 photomechanical reproduction: color; 14 x 9 cm. (Box 55, Folder 26)
    Original catalog no. GRAPHIC 1810
    Cataloging notes: Post card of staircase in the Library of Congress, Washington, D.C.
  - The Embassy Row Hotel on "the avenue of embassies", Circa 197-?]; Series 1; 1 photomechanical reproduction: color; 11 x 15 cm. (Box 55, Folder 27)
    Original catalog no. GRAPHIC 1811
    Cataloging notes: Post card.; Embassy Row Hotel at 2015 Massachusetts Ave., N.W., Washington, D.C.
    Embassy Row Hotel (Washington, D.C.) Pictorial works.; Hotels Washington (D.C.) Pictorial works.
  - New Winston Hotel: First Street and Penn Avenue., N.W., Washington, D.C., overlooking U.S. Capitol and grounds, W.A. Berkeley, prop., Circa [192-?]; Series 1; 1 photomechanical reproduction: color; 9 x 14 cm. (Box 55, Folder 28)
    Original catalog no. GRAPHIC 1812
    Cataloging notes: Post card.; Winston Hotel on Capitol Hill, Washington, D.C.
    Winston Hotel (Washington, D.C.) Pictorial works.; Hotels Washington (D.C.) Pictorial works.
  - Hans Kindler, Circa [194-?]; Series 1; 1 photographic print: black and white; 18 x 13 cm. (Box 55, Folder 29)
    Original catalog no. GRAPHIC 1813
    Cataloging notes: Title from handwritten note on verso.; Profile of bust statue of Hans Kindler.
    Kindler, Hans, 1892-1949 Portraits.; Kindler, Hans, 1892-1949. fast http://id.worldcat.org/fast/00236783; Portraits. fast http://id.worldcat.org/fast/01423831
  - The Corcoran Art Depository, Washington, D.C. photographed by Bell and Brother, Washington, D.C., Circa 1869; Series 1; 1 print: relief; image 12 x 18 cm. (Box 55, Folder 30)
    Original catalog no. GRAPHIC 1814
    Cataloging notes: From Harper's weekly, May 29, 1869, pages 340.; Building at Pennsylvania Avenue and 27th St., N.W., Washington, D.C., where Corcoran art collection was housed before the present Corcoran Gallery of Art was built.
  - Main reading room, Library of Congress by Paul Boswell., Circa [1973]; Series 1; 1 print; image 13 x 12 cm. (Box 55, Folder 31)
    Original catalog no. GRAPHIC 1815
    Cataloging notes: Dome of the main reading room at the Library of Congress.
  - The approved design of the George Washington Memorial Building: to be erected in Washington, D.C., Circa 192-?]; Series 1; 1 photomechanical reproduction; image 7 x 13 cm. (Box 55, Folder 32)
    Original catalog no. GRAPHIC 1816
    Cataloging notes: Proposed building in Washington, D.C.
    George Washington Memorial Building and Victory Memorial (Washington, D.C.) Pictorial works.
  - Freedman's Village, Arlington, Virginia, Circa 186-?]; Series 1; 1 print: relief; image 12 x 35 cm. (Box 55, Folder 33)
    Original catalog no. GRAPHIC 1817
    Cataloging notes: Newsprint image from pages 293 of unidentified publication.; Freedman's Village, Arlington County, Virginia. Many houses shown; man with rifle, woman, and 2 children in foreground.
    African Americans Virginia Arlington County Pictorial works.; Freedmen Virginia Arlington County Pictorial works.; African Americans. fast http://id.worldcat.org/fast/00799558; Freedmen. fast http://id.worldcat.org/fast/00933987; Freedman's Village (Arlington County, Va.) Pictorial works.; Virginia Arlington County. fast http://id.worldcat.org/fast/01219848; Virginia Freedman's Village (Arlington County) fast http://id.worldcat.org/fast/01878086; Pictorial works. fast http://id.worldcat.org/fast/01423874
  - Rev. Byron Sunderland, D.D. photograph by McCartey [sic]; engraved by J.C. Buttre., Circa 1860]; Series 1; 1 print: engraving; image 23 x 14 cm. (Box 55, Folder 34)
    Original catalog no. GRAPHIC 1820
    Cataloging notes: Plate from: The Union pulpit: a collection of sermons by ministers of different denominations. Washington: W.T. Smithson, for the Young Men's Christian Association of Washington, D.C., 1860.; Sheet trimmed to or within plate mark.; Bust portrait of this Presbyterian minister and chaplain of the U.S. Senate (1861-1864 and 1873-1879).
  - Rev. C.M. Butler, D.D.: rector of Trinity Parish, Washington, D.C. photograph by McCartey [sic]; engraved by J.C. Buttre., Circa 1860]; Series 1; 1 print: engraving; image 23 x 14 cm. (Box 55, Folder 35)
    Original catalog no. GRAPHIC 1821
    Cataloging notes: Plate from: The Union pulpit: a collection of sermons by ministers of different denominations. Washington: W.T. Smithson, for the Young Men's Christian Association of Washington, D.C., 1860.; Sheet trimmed to or within plate mark.; Bust portrait of this Episcopal priest.